Preliminary Inventory to the George Halonen Miscellaneous Papers, 1918-1922
Hoover Institution Archives
George Halonen Miscellaneous Papers,
1918-1922
XX126
Halonen, George
1 manuscript box. (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, reports, and printed matter, relating to activities of the Finnish Information Bureau in the United States in publicizing and seeking American recognition of the Soviet government of Finland. Includes writings and correspondence of Santeri Nuorteva, head of the Finnish Information Bureau.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Martens, L. K. (Liudvig Karlovich), 1875-1948.; Finnish Information Bureau (New York); Cooperative societies--Karelia (Russia); Finland.; Finland--Foreign relations--United States.; Finland--History--Revolution, 1917-1918.; Karelia (Russia)--Economic conditions.; Karelia (Russia)--History.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--Finland.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation)
Container List
- Address delivered by S. Nuorteva on the Finnish situation.
- Agreement between George Halonen, representative of the Karelian Worker's Commune and the Robert Dollar Company for the purchase of mica. 1922.
- Agreement between L. A. Martens, representative of the R.S.F.S.R., and Michael Cohen, Importer and Exporter, New York. 16 September 1919.
- Authorizations, certificates, mandates, etc.
- "The Case for Russia". 18 May 1918.
- Contract of merchandise purchases between National Storage Company and the Russian Socialist Federal Republic. 16 September 1919.
- "A Crisis in Civilization" 1918
- Correspondence
  - Tchticherin
  - Miscellaneous
- "The Czecho-Slovaks" 1918
- "Finland - Russia"
- "Finland and the Russian Border" by Santeri Nuorteva
- "Finland's Bitter Struggle" by Santeri Nuorteva
- "Finland's Future"
- "Finland's Struggle for Freedom by Representative to U.S." by Santeri Nuorteva
- "Finnish Organizations" by Santeri Nuorteva
- Finnish Workers Government. Central Committee. Foreign Department.
  - Proclamation
- "A Gag for British Labor"
- "The German Menace in Finland, White Guard Intrigues Have Enlarged Scope of Kaiser's Imperialistic Plans" by Santeri Nuorteva
- "German Methods" 8 Jun 1918
- "Horrible Conditions in Finnish Prison Camps"
- "The Iron Cross"
- Karelian Economic Council 1921
- Karelian Executive
- "The Last Card" 1918
- Memorandum by L. A. Martens, representative of the R.S.F.S.R., regarding opening of commercial relations with United States.
- Memorandum on Finland's Relief by Santeri Nuorteva
- Memorandum - Russia - The Soviet Government
  (John Reed's brief to the U.S. State Department)
- "A New Holy Alliance" 1918
- Nuorteva, Santeri
  - General
  - Correspondence file 1918-19
- Peoples Republic of Finland. Council of Peoples Commissars. Proclamation March 18, 1918
- "Potpourri Russe" 1918
- "Pro-Germanism in Russia"
- "The Round Peg" 1918
- "Self-Government for Finland"
- "The Semenioff Collapse"
- "Shall the Finnish Workers be Slaves" by Santeri Nuorteva
- "Sinister Rhetoric" 1918
- "Slavery in Finland" by Santeri Nuorteva
- "The Smoke Screen Over Russia" (Call editoria) 1 Jul 1918
- "A Socialist Delegation Sails"
- Statement by Santeri Nuorteva, representative in the U.S. of the Provisional Revolutionary Government of the People's Republic of Finland
- Statement of George Halonen, representative of the Karelian Worker's Commune in the United States. 29 June 1922. Washington, D.C.
- Statement on Finland by Santeri Nuorteva
- "Story of the Karelian Worker's Commune" by George Halonen
  (clipping from the Federated Press)
- "Suspending Intelligence" 1918
- "To Wipe Out the Balkan Plague Spot"
- "The Work of the American Representative of the Finnish Worker's Government, reported by the Finnish Information Bureau"
- Miscellaneous typescripts, notes, reports, etc.